Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
Kimi yo hashire
You must run forth!
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Kyodai na teki o
You must fight the towering foe!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Kimi yo tsukame
You must seize the power!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
A half-century has passed since humanity began moving...
...its burgeoning population into space.
These gigantic space colonies orbiting the Earth...
...became a second home to humanity...
...where people were born and raised...
...and where they died.
It is the year 0079 of the Universal Century.
The colonies of Side 3 proclaimed themselves
the Principality of Zeon.
It launched a war of independence
against the Earth Federation.
During this war, the Principality of Zeon
and the Federation...
...caused the deaths
of half the total population.
Humanity was horrified by its own actions.
Garma Strikes
The Earth-based Zeon air force?
One squadron has been deployed
from the Gaw attack carrier!
That's quite a number.
Relative speed, Mach.78.
Steady as she goes.
Actually, its position isn't optimal.
I see it! Its approach angle is too low!
Right, I see what you mean.
I'd like to do it in one try. All right?
Roger! Standby, laser lock!
Whenever you're ready.
Laser sensor released! Let's do it.
Good. Looking good, looking good.
Captain Garma, Musai capsule is on board.
Hello, Char.
It's not like you to be burned
by just one Federation ship.
Don't say it, Garma.
Or should I call you Captain Garma Zabi,
commander of the Earth Occupation Force?
Just call me Garma, like you did
back at the military academy.
There's the Trojan Horse there.
Right.
To think the man they call the Red Comet...
...couldn't take down that ship.
Are you trying to tell me
that your time is too valuable to waste here?
No... Think of it as a good friend
coming to meet you, Char.
I remind you that ship made it
through the atmosphere.
Right.
Taking that as a starting point,
we're calculating its fighting strength now.
I guess you've been on constant duty
since the guerrilla mop-up operation.
Get some rest.
I accept your kind suggestion.
However... I guarantee that they'll award you
the Zeon Cross for this.
Thank you...
For giving me the opportunity
to prove myself.
Are you here to help me
finally impress my older sister?
Don't laugh. The men are watching.
We're short of spare parts in Block 20.
Just be careful with the electrical systems!
The joint hydraulics are normal.
I'll measure the balancer.
If I find even one dud, you'll be sorry!
Don't worry.
Well, well, Hayato. You sure are ambitious!
But the real enemy is right in front of us.
Can you improve in time?
Quit teasing me.
Kai, aren't you responsible
for maintaining the tank?
It's done.
Then please standby at level 1 battle stations.
What about you?
We couldn't see you when we checked
the bridge's monitor.
Bright ordered me to look for you.
Good work.
The solution is to deploy the Gundam.
It's the only way to break through
the Zeon lines!
Amuro needs to get some rest.
But unlike your previous battles,
this time they've got all their forces in place.
We'll just have to wait and see what they do.
I'm in command here!
Take the Gundam and one Core Fighter...
...and break through the middle!
Hey! Knock it off, you little brat!
Bright! Launch interceptor missiles!
All personnel, return fire.
Don't let the Dopps near the White Base.
Damn you, Trojan Horse!
Dopps coming around the stern!
They want to block our escape!
Bright! You're ignoring orders!
The Dopps attacked before
the order was executed.
Mr. Bright, I'm ready to go.
Amuro.
Ms. Sayla briefed me on the situation.
Are you all right?
If you push yourself too hard,
you'll just make yourself vulnerable.
Really think you can do it, Amuro?
It's not a question of confidence.
I just have to do it. Right, Mr. Bright?
That's right.
Bright! Let the Gundam go!
Let me remind you that the Gundam
wasn't built for mid-air combat!
And Amuro's not trained for it.
Um, this probably won't become
a close combat situation.
How about we use the Guntank
to shoot down the enemy?
That way, it won't be as hard on Amuro.
Hayato...
I understand.
Hurry up and transfer the Gundam's
cockpit to the Guntank.
Leave two Core Fighters
here for interception.
Is that acceptable, sir?
Can we break through?
Who knows?
Hamble, continue pursuing the enemy ship.
Roger, Captain!
When the Guevil squadron gets in front,
we'll initiate attack. Guevil, go!
Guevil squadron, launch!
Guntank, hurry with the transfer!
Why is the enemy's attack
so restrained, Bright?
They want to take the White Base
without damaging it.
Descend, Mirai.
Yes, sir.
We can't let the Zeons have this ship!
Guntank top portion, transferred.
Guntank assembly, confirmed.
Mr. Bright, I'm awaiting your orders.
Hayato, are you ready?
- Got it. Leave it to me.
- Guntank, proceed to launch pad and wait.
Guntank, proceed to launch pad and wait.
Proceeding slowly.
He's totally overworked, but...
Amuro, when we launch from the White Base,
move away from the ship!
We'll break up their formation!
I have to disagree.
Think about it...
The enemy is after the White Base.
We can't cover it from far away.
No, Amuro.
The Guntank can attract their attention...
...and we can split up the enemy forces...
Hayato. You just shoot down
as many enemies as possible.
I won't let you use the mountains as a shield.
Advance the ground forces.
We're going to capture the enemy ship.
Altitude, 105 meters.
White Base holding steady.
Guntank, okay to launch.
Amuro, you are okay to launch.
Correct for balance and descend.
Roger! Set to launch!
Ready, Hayato?!
Let's go!
What the hell's that?! Looks like a tank.
Which way, Hayato?!
Turn to the rear right!
What fire power!
What's that?
G-Ground forces!
Use the mountains as a shield...
and break through with the Guntank.
The air teams will be obstructed
and unable to attack so easily.
What's going on?!
Enemy ground forces!
What?!
They're Magella Attack tanks!
Retreat! Fall back! No, turn around!
Idiots! Where are you aiming!
Forward cannons, concentrate fire on
Magella Attacks!
Aren't you going to retreat?!
This is your first time in the White Base.
We have more experience than you.
Why, you! That's insubordination!
Will you be satisfied if we break through
the enemy's siege?
All right.
We'll take over.
We can handle it.
I just have to pull this, right?
Yeah, thanks.
Incredible! You're hitting them!
Amuro! As long as we're positioned
in front of the White Base...
...the enemy will increase their sorties.
We can't leave the White Base.
We'll just have to bust open an escape route.
Amuro! It's Bright!
Do me a favor. The Guntank isn't mobile
enough to combat the Magella Attack tanks.
Can you go in with the Gundam?
Mr. Bright!
Please, I'm begging you.
Ryu will man the Guntank.
Mr. Bright.
Amuro! It's just as Mr. Bright says!
The Magella Attack tanks are...
Maybe it's easier to fight alone.
I understand.
Please have Kai or Ms. Sayla
pilot the Guntank.
I'm sure Ms. Sayla can do it.
We're nothing but fish in a barrel here.
We need to split their fighting strength
by separating from the White Base.
Mobile Suit
A report, sir.
We have information that the tank
is a new type of mobile suit.
That's a mobile suit? I see...
So, that's the Federation's new mobile suit.
Yes, sir. Its firepower is far above
that of a conventional tank.
We'll fight mobile suits with mobile suits.
We should have three.
Yes, sir.
Send instructions to the siege forces.
If the enemy makes it to the sea,
they may escape to Federation airspace.
Stop them from advancing any further.
Understood?!
Yes, sir!
We don't have time to transfer
the Core Fighter.
You must run, Amuro!
Roger!
Are you really taking it?
I have no choice.
Drink this. It's a nutrition drink.
This is all I can do for you, but...
Thanks.
Good luck!
I'm counting on you!
Ryu, if you're not feeling confident, it's okay.
There's no choice. Launching!
It's not like I'm doing this
because I'm overly confident...
Amuro, did you say something?
No...
Amuro, Gundam, launching!
Don't rush into battle.
Standby until the Guntank's been launched.
Waiting... It's always like this.
Of course Garma is having a hard time.
He's demonstrating why we twice failed
to capture the Federation secret.
And what's more, he has more
fighting strength than we did.
Huh?
Vice Admiral Dozle will recognize that
the failure was not due to my shortcoming.
I see.
Is Garma piloting a mobile suit?
No, sir.
So, Garma chose not to suit up.
He could die in battle against the Gundam...
Or, I could step in and save his hide.
That had been my plan, but...
The Guntank is in front.
If I'm to be in front of the Guntank...
...then I have to get away from
the White Base like Hayato said.
Gundam! Amuro!
Yes, Ms. Sayla?
Time to launch.
There are three Zakus out there.
Be careful, Amuro.
Right.
I can't ask a woman how we should fight.
If only Bright had been clear at the outset...!
Launching!
I'm falling!
Mr. Ryu!
What's that?
Kai, fall back! The Gundam will get the rest!
Thanks! Hayato's a sitting duck right now!
Bastard!
Mr. Ryu! Behind you!
The enemy's mobile suit has a beam rifle!
What ferocious power!
Wh-What are they doing?
Amuro!
Why, you...!
They're not going to get me! No way...!
Divide the enemy's attention!
Split up the offense!
All right. Let's do it!
There it is!
Got him!
You bastard!
Amuro! You...
All right, then!
We're returning to base.
Just like that, Captain?
You saw the enemy's power.
I want the ship and the mobile suit intact.
That power requires us
to totally reassess our war strategy.
Just don't let them leave this continent.
Make sure I can keep an eye on them.
I'll get them, no matter the cost!
Bright.
I know. We'll have to enter the continent
along the mountain range.
That's right.
Although it may be Garma Zabi's domain...
...there should be a Federation resistance
still active in the continent.
But how do we make contact?
Bright, everyone's counting on you
right now.
I know, Mirai.
Well, let's welcome our
Gundam warrior home.
Amuro. Well done.
Amuro.
- Amuro! Hey!
- Way to go!
Thanks for the hard work!
Huh! Look at him, acting all cool.
The Gundam wasn't the only one fighting.
Stop saying things like that!
Amuro! We baked a celebration pie for you
as fast as we could!
We brought Champagne too, Amuro!
Let's celebrate with pie!
Cheers, Amuro! Cheers, Amuro!
Just leave me alone, all right?
What's your problem, Amuro?!
Char.
Oh, Garma.
Why didn't you tell me how devastating
that secret weapon is?
I did.
I told you it was Zeon Cross material.
Already thinking about your next plan?
Yes. I can't miss a beat.
I'll do what I can.
I'd be honored to give you a hand.
I'd appreciate it.
Having you is like having a hundred men.
And I'll be able to prove myself
to my older sister Kycilia as well.
Isn't Lady Kycilia your direct superior?
Char.
What is it?
I have a good friend in you.
Don't get all sentimental on me now.
In order to make contact
with Federation HQ...
...Amuro is sent on a mission
to fly over enemy lines.
But Char seeks to nip this plan in the bud.
Can the Core Fighter transfer to the Gundam
and do battle against Char?
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
The Core Fighter's Escape.
Next Time
The Core Fighter's Escape
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...